<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Joshua Kim</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Joshua Kim</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>About</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey! I&amp;rsquo;m Joshua, an incoming junior at Troy High School. As of recent, I&amp;rsquo;ve been finding myself in cybersecurity, math, music, and my school&amp;rsquo;s NJROTC unit. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick breakdown:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;cybersecurity&#34;&gt;Cybersecurity
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;ve always found myself around computers since I was young, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until I entered 8th grade that I was introduced to the topic through &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.uscyberpatriot.org&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;CyberPatriot&lt;/a&gt;, a nationwide competition for middle and high schoolers run by the Air &amp;amp; Space Forces Administration. I&amp;rsquo;m the team captain of Runtime Terror, a CyberPatriot team that&amp;rsquo;s gone to the national finals (the top 12 out of thousands of teams!) every year since our inception in 2021. I&amp;rsquo;ve personally been to nationals twice so far, which take the format of an RvB with some amusing network topologies. Each trip to nationals has been incredibly eye-opening, stress-inducing, and thrilling experiences that keep my love for cybersecurity going strong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;My passion for math is really driven by a deep love for logical thinking and problem-solving. It just happens that these skills manifest themselves most clearly through math olympiads. I&amp;rsquo;ve been participating in the AMC competitions since the seventh grade, and have qualified for the American Invitational Mathematics Examination (AIME) twice so far. You can also find me at various local math competitions in my area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;Music
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;My family is deep into music. Everyone on my mom&amp;rsquo;s side of the family are musicians, and my dad grew up listening and playing lots of music. So whether it&amp;rsquo;s from the environment I grew up in or genetics, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that I also have a blooming interest in music. I personally play the piano, which has been a part of my life for the better part of the last five years. You might also be able to find covers that I&amp;rsquo;ve made of some songs on YouTube (that link &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; be hidden somewhere on this website).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;njrotc&#34;&gt;NJROTC
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Troy has one of the biggest JROTC units in the country. As such, I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself forging some of my closest friendships in the unit and found a strong sense of &amp;ldquo;home&amp;rdquo; there. As one of the current color guard division heads, I&amp;rsquo;ve stepped into a leadership position for the incoming year, renewing my excitement for JROTC and opening new doors for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;everything-else&#34;&gt;Everything else!
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a quick a rundown of my academics. But what makes me &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are just a couple things I like to do in my free time (a constantly updating list):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching movies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Play puzzle games with my friends (OK &amp;amp; KL, my goats)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go for a drive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on felicity (my Linux script), my one and only true love&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work out at the gym&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
