<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Movies on Joshua Kim</title>
        <link>https://joshuak.im/movies/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Movies on Joshua Kim</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 21:40:12 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joshuak.im/movies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <link>https://joshuak.im/movies/kpop-demon-hunters/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 21:40:12 -0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://joshuak.im/movies/kpop-demon-hunters/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://joshuak.im/movies/kpop-demon-hunters/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post KPop Demon Hunters" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before I get into the actual movie, can we talk about that name? Like, I get that it&amp;rsquo;s probably hard to think of a title for a movie like this. But KPop Demon Hunters could not have been the best choice. It just makes the movie feel so much more childish than it should be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put it into a few words, the movie exceeded my expectations. By a lot. You go into the movie expecting it to be a kids movie – one that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have actual themes and complex characters like this movie has. You definitely don&amp;rsquo;t expect scenes like the ones where Rumi asks Celine (who was essentially her mother) to kill her with her own sword.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rumi&amp;rsquo;s character development throughout the movie is shockingly well-made. The frustration she feels about her patterns and identity parallel similar conflicts that people have in life. Her friendship with Zoey and Mira just feels so real – with the overwhelming support she gets and the frustrations she has with each of them. And her conflict with Jinu dances so satisfyingly along that edge between enemies and lovers throughout the whole movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The animation is also pretty good, especially for a film that was never intended for release in theaters. Being animated by Sony, who&amp;rsquo;s been pretty busy breaking their back carrying Western animation for the past decade or so, it&amp;rsquo;s no surprise that the scenes look beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the biggest part for me was how prominent Korean culture was in the movie. Although it is an American film, the background in every scene captures the essence of Korea so well, and there&amp;rsquo;s just enough of the culture mixed in for it to feel normal for foreign fans, but authentic for Korean fans as well. Especially through their choice of voice actors and singers, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that Netflix put in effort to make the film feel convincingly Korean. Getting well-known actors like Ahn Hyo-seop, Lee Byung-hun, and especially getting Twice to cover Takedown, definitely gets the film some cookie points in the Korean department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I would have liked to see a little more of the other characters though. We only got a few lines from every Saja Boy apart from Jinu, and Zoey and Mira just felt like side characters purely created to highlight Rumi. While I get that HUNTR/X was formed around Rumi, the movie really doesn&amp;rsquo;t bother to give Zoey and Mira much backstory at all. And we know almost nothing about the other Saja Boys. I guess we know one of them has abs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But overall, I came out of the movie with vastly different thoughts than I came into it with. The movie had real emotional weight, with jokes that were actually funny, and sad scenes that were &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; sad, not just &amp;ldquo;womp womp&amp;rdquo; sad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the music slaps. The music is super catchy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Still Walking (2008)</title>
        <link>https://joshuak.im/movies/still-walking/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 01:41:25 -0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://joshuak.im/movies/still-walking/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://joshuak.im/movies/still-walking/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Still Walking (2008)" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stripped of plot twists and Hollywood-esque drama, simplicity drives the beauty of Still Walking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the course of a little over 24 hours, Still Walking follows the Yokoyama family&amp;rsquo;s memorial for their eldest son Junpei. The parents, Kyohei and Toshiko Yokoyama, host their two remaining children Ryota and Chinami at their house for the day. Junpei&amp;rsquo;s death was particularly difficult for the parents, as he was the favorite of the three and was destined to continue the family clinic, the lifelong pride of his father Kyohei. While Kyohei had some hope left for Ryota, Ryota instead became an art restorer and is often between jobs, which the father is still conflicted over. To make matters worse, Ryota married Yukari, a widow with a son from her previous marriage, a marriage that both parents (especially his mother) still haven&amp;rsquo;t accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;family&#34;&gt;Family
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The parents aren&amp;rsquo;t the only ones with gripes: there&amp;rsquo;s tension between everyone in the family. Ryota&amp;rsquo;s stepson refuses to call him &amp;ldquo;dad&amp;rdquo;, struggling to understand how Ryota fits in his own family. Toshiko, with her signature passive-aggressiveness, wants Ryota to have a son of his own. And crucially, Yukari just wants the Yokoyama family to treat Atsushi as their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s never confrontation in the family. Through their gripes, the family just acts like a family: eating together, asking for recipes, gossiping about other people. The only glimpses we get into what each person really thinks are in small, isolated scenes – scenes where the family isn&amp;rsquo;t together. Otherwise, when the family is together, each of the characters demonstrate restraint in both a uniquely Japanese way and a universally understandable fashion. Ryota does his best to keep talking with his dad, and calms his worries by pretending he has a job. Toshiko keeps conversation with Yukari, who is extremely good-spirited and kind, with Toshiko even gifting her a kimono at the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s really what makes family. The love is never perfect – expectations feel too high, and there&amp;rsquo;s never a perfect understanding between everyone. But there&amp;rsquo;s an everlasting link that brings them together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;grief&#34;&gt;Grief
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;When Yoshio shows up – the fat, unemployed, and &amp;ldquo;loser&amp;rdquo;-like classmate that Junpei died saving – Toshiko feels incredible grief thinking that her son&amp;rsquo;s life was lost for a man like him. In an incredibly powerful scene where Ryota asks why the family still invites him after fifteen years, Toshiko states, &amp;ldquo;Not having someone to hate makes it all the worse for me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on in the day, Toshiko asks Ryota about the name of a sumo wrestler that she can&amp;rsquo;t seem to remember. He can&amp;rsquo;t seem to remember either, which bugs her for the rest of the day. As Ryota leaves the town and the bus departs, he remembers the name, remarking, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s always like that, I&amp;rsquo;m always a little late.&amp;rdquo; That was the last day that Ryota saw his parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And at the very end of the film, through a voiceover, Ryota tells us that he never got to watch a soccer game with his dad, or give his mom a ride in a car – something that his parents always wished to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s only human nature to miss opportunities: opportunities to forgive, opportunities to love. Written in thoughts of his own late mother, Kore-eda surely understands this well. And while there is a &amp;ldquo;life is fleeting&amp;rdquo; message to be said, it&amp;rsquo;s really about grief. The inevitability of lingering grief in the cycle of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-thoughts&#34;&gt;My thoughts!
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kore-eda&amp;rsquo;s orchestration of all these different scenes is nothing short of masterful. The characters seem so genuine and the scenes so real that you feel like you&amp;rsquo;ve just been plopped in the Yokoyama home for a day. It&amp;rsquo;s really the small details (which there are SO many of) that give the film such a profound feeling, something that has always been Kore-eda&amp;rsquo;s strong suit. Throughout the entire two hours of the film, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like a single second is wasted – every scene has weight and importance in the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also an incredibly attractive style that the movie has when the plot is driven by these small details rather than action or plot twists. It&amp;rsquo;s helped by the actors, who really excel in their roles. Kirin Kiki, playing the role of Toshiko, creates a perfect persona for the calm yet snide person that Toshiko is. The child actor for Atsushi, Shohei Tanaka, is incredible in creating a nuanced, complicated character while still feeling just like a kid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yes, the film isn&amp;rsquo;t perfect. The subtlety definitely isn&amp;rsquo;t for everyone – Owen Gleiberman from Entertainment Weekly calls it &amp;ldquo;fetishistic&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;a tad frustrating&amp;rdquo;, which is understandable considering the extremely different approach that Kore-eda loves to take. But the power behind Kore-eda&amp;rsquo;s ability to convey emotion is not to be underestimated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
